

Mua Ndzo Laurent

Software Engineer

Last Update: 23/10/2019



Professional Summary

Self-motivated Web Developer with decent but yet great experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in role with company promoting best practices and offering diverse customer projects. Determined Web/Android Developer offering more than +3 years of expertise in fast-paced departments. Bilingual and well spoken with ability to work closely with people of all different backgrounds and personalities.



Work History

2018-02 -2019-07

Software Developer

Multiconcept, Douala, Littoral

TECH STACK: PHP, Linux, Shell, JavaScript, CSS3,HTML5, Shared Hosting, Android, Laravel, Lumen, Python, Django, nodejs, app-engine, google cloud,

- Build scalable web and mobile applications for the enterprise using nodejs, laravel and android. Built some using the django framwork
- Built backend API using the lumen framework to communicate with in-house mobile applications for survey
- Designed, implemented and monitored web platforms and sites for continuous improvement
- Deployed applications to popular web host serves such as heruko, hostinger, namecheap, bluehosts and google cloud

2016-06 -2018-01

Web Application Developer

Nkeksi Inc, Buea, Buea

TECH STACK: PHP, Laravel, Linux, Shell, JavaScript, CSS3,HTML5, Shared Hosting, Android, Python

- Built and styled new mobile-friendly websites and transitioned old site into mobile-friendly version
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement and managed git repositories



Address

Bonamoussadi, Douala Cameroon, LT, 00000

Phone

237670518086

E-mail

muarachmann@gmail.com

Twitter

https://twitter.com/muaRachma nn

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mua-ndzo-laurent-40ba5

www

https://muarachmann.github.io/



HTML5 & CSS3



PHP



Python



Javascript



Laravel



Django



API design knowledge



Web Development

Native

French

Designed mobile application and self hosted on the playstore

- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects
- Strengthened company brand and identity by creating distinctive website and logo
- Established web hosting for site and uploaded site files to hosting account



Education

2008-09 -2013-06

GCE - O LEVEL: General Studies

Government Bilingual Practising High School - Yaounde Obtained 24/30 points.

2013-09 -2015-07

GCE - A LEVEL: Science

Government Bilingual Practising High School - Yaounde

Obtained 21/25 points. Maths - A, Physics - A, Biology - A,

Further Maths - B, Chemistry - C

2015-10 -Current

Bachelors of Computer Engineering: Software Engineering

University of Buea - Molyko, Buea

- · Active member of google developers club
- Worked in team to design and Implement a result management system (RESTAT) for the faculty
- Graduated in Top 5% of Class
- Graduated with 3.5/4 GPA
- Elected to Course delegate for Database Design/Practice and Java mobile Programming (Android)



Accomplishments

- Designed and implemented (group of three) a tool for the statistical analysis of results for the University currently used at the faculty that resulted in a complete transformation of the manual system to an automated one
- Re-designed and implemented a cross-platform installation process for the EHR(Electronic Health Record) platform for the LibreHealth Organization as part of my volunteerism in the open source community
- Successfully completed Google Summer Of Code and was

immediately promoted to a Mentor where I mentored Google code in and Google Summer of Code the following year including other programs like Outreachy

- Awarded as winning mentor for Google Code in 2018 under DIAL
- Successfully completed the Google Africa Award scholarship and made it to the final project phase [certification pending]
- Built a highly scalable, robust and customizable e-commerce jewellery platform from scratch using the laravel framework and deployed on the app-engine flex environment using gcloud tool



Certifications

2015-08 Vocational Qualification Certificate (Web Development) Institute of Science and Innovate Technology of Africa

2018-08 • Google Summer of Code

2018-12 • Google Code In (Mentor)

2019-08 Google Summer of Code (Mentor)